A Guide to the Research Papers of Joanne S. Lawson concerning Rose Greely, ca. 1912-2002
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Research Papers of Joanne S. Lawson concerning Rose Greely ca. 1912-2002
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10772 -c, -d
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Manuscript accession 10772-c was given to the University of Virginia Library by Joanne Lawson Wilson, Houston, Texas on June 6, 2003 and Manuscript accession 10772-d was given through Judith B. Tankard, Landscape Historian, Waban, Massachusetts, on May 3, 2004.
Scope and Content
This addition to the papers of Rose Greely consists of the research files compiled by Joanne S. Lawson concerning Greely and her work for her thesis Rose Greely, FASLA Her Life and Work (1993), ca. 1912-2002, ca. 2,000 items (7 Hollinger boxes, 3 linear feet). Included are copies of correspondence, published articles on landscape architecture by Greely, published articles about her work, files concerning various clients or projects of Greely, notes, negatives, slides and photographs. Of interest is a copy of her thesis in the School of Domestic Architecture and Landscape Architecture at Cambridge, Massachusetts (1920) on a proposed cooperative farm community.
Arrangement
The two collections of research material on Rose Greely have been interfiled and arranged alphabetically by title of the folder.
Contents List
- Architectural Drawings, 1938-1959 (Oversize Box 1)
  Rose Greely, Conway, New Hampshire, Cabin Plans (1938); Mr. & Mrs. Richard Harkness, Washington, D.C. Grading Plan, Retaining Wall, Planting Plan (1946, 1951); Mrs. R.M. Kauffman, Washington, D.C. and Chevy Chase, Maryland, Study of Perennial Beds, Rose Garden, Perennial Borders, and Construction Plan of Garden (1942-1949, 1959); and Dr. Paul Y. Rosenberg, Washington, D.C., General Design & Planting Plan (1941)
- Article- Remarkable Foundations Rose Ishbel Greely, Landscape Architect, by Joanne Seal Lawson, 1997-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Articles by Rose Greely (Published), 1912-1935 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Articles concerning the Gardens of Rose Greely, 1922-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Articles concerning or mentioning Rose Greely, 1941, 1969, 1989, n.d. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Azalea Rose Greely, 1987, n.d. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Biographical Information- Adolphus W. Greely, 1897-1994, n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Biographical Information concerning Rose Greely, 1934, 1997, n.d. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Book Proposal, n.d. (Box-folder 1:8)
- The Cambridge School of Architecture and Landscape Architecture, 1919-1991, n.d. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Anna M. Carrere, 1931-1942, 1998, n.d. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Client File List, n.d. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Client Files- Aberdeen Proving Ground, Study of Commanding Officers Quarters, Aberdeen, Maryland, 1934-1935, 1934, 1941, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 1:12)
- Client Files- Miss Mary B. Adams, 1934 (Box-folder 1:13)
- Client Files- Army and Navy Country Club, Arlington, Virginia, 1934 (Box-folder 1:14)
- Client Files- The Arts Club, Eye Street NW, Washington, D.C., 1934, 1946, 1971, 1996, n.d. (Box-folder 1:15)
- Client Files- Dr. and Mrs. Philip Bard, 6 Meadow Road, Baltimore, Maryland, 1951-1954, 1953 (Box-folder 1:16)
- Client Files- James M. Barnes, Montevideo, 1947-1950, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 1:17)
- Client Files- Peter Belin, Washington, D.C., 1934, 1953, n.d. (Box-folder 1:18)
- Client Files- Leo M. Bernstein, 2425 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C., 1952, 1953 (Box-folder 1:19)
- Client Files- Francis Biddle, 1669 31st Street NW, Washington, D.C., 1947-1949, n.d. (Box-folder 1:20)
- Client Files- Robert Woods Bliss Garden, 28th and O Streets NW, Washington, D.C., n.d. (Box-folder 1:21)
- Client Files- Eugene Bogan, 3115 Cleveland Avenue NW, Washington, D.C., n.d. (Box-folder 1:23)
- Client Files- General and Mrs. K.C. Bolton, Dumbarton Ave., Washington, D.C., n.d. (Box-folder 1:24)
- Client Files- Karl Boy-Ed- Callander,- Berryville, Virginia, 1951, 1934, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 2:1)
- Client Files- James C. Brady, Gardens at Mill House, Far Mills, New Jersey, 1933-1935, 1934 (Box-folder 2:2)
- Client Files- William Bradford, Langely Farms, McLean, Virginia, 1946-1947, 1996, n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Client Files- David Bruce, 1411 34th Street NW, Washington, D.C., 1955, 1955, n.d. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Client Files- Wiley T. Buchanan, 4220 Nebraska Avenue NW, Washington, D.C., 1955, 1992 (Box-folder 2:5)
- Client Files- William A.M. Burden, 1224 30th Street NW, Washington, D.C., n.d. (Box-folder 2:6)
- Client Files- Mrs. Edward Burling, 1932, 1937, 1934, 1989, n.d. (Box-folder 2:7)
- Client Files- Morris Cafritz, 2301 Foxhall Road, NW, Washington, D.C. 1937-1938, 1977, 1984, 1993, n.d. (Box-folder 2:8)
- Client Files- Margaret Camp, 3435 Springland Lane, Washington, D.C., n.d. (Box-folder 2:9)
- Client Files- Carrolsburg Dwellings, 1936-1943, n.d. (Box-folder 2:10)
- Client Files- General and Mrs. Charles Douglas, Cemetery Lot Bench and Marker, 1948, 1948 (Box-folder 2:11)
- Client Files- William Chase, n.d. (Box-folder 2:12)
- Client Files- A Child's Playhouse and Garden, n.d. (Box-folder 2:13)
- Client Files- General and Mrs. William Conner, 2421 Tracy Place NW, Washington, D.C., 1941, 1948, n.d. (Box-folder 2:14)
- Client Files- Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C., 1941, n.d. (Box-folder 2:15)
- Client Files- J. Harry Covington, Minden Cottage, Craftsbury Vermont, 1934-1937, 1997, n.d. (Box-folder 2:16)
- Client Files- Mrs. J. Harry Covington, 2320 Wyoming Avenue NW, Washington, D.C., 1936, 1940, 1936, 1992, n.d. (Box-folder 2:17)
- Client Files- Whitman Cross, Chevy Chase, Maryland, 1928, 1915-1934, 1982-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 2:18)
- Client Files- Samuel J. Decker, 2700 Chesapeake Street, Washington, D.C., 1954, n.d. (Box-folder 2:19)
- Client Files- Mr. and Mrs. Beverly Duer, Woodburn, Leesburg, Virginia, 1946-1949, n.d. (Box-folder 2:20)
- Client Files- Miss Ruth Eddy, Old Bennington, Vermont, 1954, n.d. (Box-folder 2:21)
- Client Files- Mr. and Mrs. Elmer, Jr., n.d. (Box-folder 2:22)
- Client Files- Mrs. Henry D. Erwin, Arbremont Perennial Garden, 1935, 1935, 1999, n.d. (Box-folder 2:23)
- Client Files- Colonel and Mrs. Robert H. Fletcher, Leesburg, Virginia, 1937-1938, n.d. (Box-folder 2:24)
- Client Files- John Clifford Folger, 2991 Woodland Avenue, Washington, D.C., 1942-1951, 1940-1954, 1993-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 2:25)
- Client Files- Friends Meeting House, 1997-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 2:26)
- Client Files- Garden Club of America, Rock Creek Park, Washington, D.C., 1932, 1933, n.d. (Box-folder 2:27)
- Client Files- Mrs. J.O. Gawne, 2439 Tracy Place NW, Washington, D.C., 1943, n.d. (Box-folder 2:28)
- Client Files- Miss Mary Gore, River Road, Potomac Maryland, 1950-1951, n.d. (Box-folder 2:29)
- Client Files- Rose Greely, Summer Cottage, Still Pond, [Conway, New Hampshire], 1937, n.d. (Box-folder 2:30)
- Client Files- Rose Greely, 3131 O Street, Washington, D.C., n.d. (Box-folder 2:31)
- Client Files- John Guider, n.d. (Box-folder 2:32)
- Client Files- Emma T. Hahm, 6036 Oregon Avenue, Washington, D.C., 1926-1927, 1929-1937, n.d. (Box-folder 2:33)
- Client Files- Chandler Hale, 1934-1935, n.d. (Box-folder 2:34)
- Client Files- Richard Harkness, 3035 Dumbarton Avenue, Washington, D.C., 1947, n.d. (Box-folder 2:35)
- Client Files- Hartwood Acres Park, 215 Saronburg Blvd.; Pittsburg, Pennsylvania, 1939, 1950, 1997 (Box-folder 2:36)
- Client Files- Mrs. Gabriel Hauge, 3500 Lowell Street NW, Washington, D.C., 1953, 1953 (Box-folder 2:37)
- Client Files- William R. Hearst, 2202 Decatur Place NW, Washington, D.C., 1948, n.d. (Box-folder 3:1)
- Client Files- Mrs. Hendrick, Bellevue, Warrenton, Virginia, 1946-1947, 1946 (Box-folder 3:2)
- Client Files- Mrs. William Hurd Hill, 1943, n.d. (Box-folder 3:3)
- Client Files- Gilbert Hitchcock, 4936 Loughboro Road, Washington, D.C., 1936, n.d. (Box-folder 3:4)
- Client Files- Arthur J. Holden, Bennington Vermont, 1939, 1934 (Box-folder 3:5)
- Client Files- A.B. Houghton, 3003 Massachusetts Avenue, NW, Washington, D.C., 1934 (Box-folder 3:6)
- Client Files- Henry S. Huidekoper, Millwood Land and Loughboro Road, 1959, n.d. (Box-folder 3:7)
- Client Files- L.E. Jeffries, Muckross Estate, Fairfax County Virginia, 1929, 1929, 1934 (Box-folder 3:8)
- Client Files- Jubal Early Civilian Housing Project, Arlington, Virginia, 1940s, 1997-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 3:9)
- Client Files- Rudolph M. Kauffman, Magnolia Parkway 7, Chevy Chase Maryland, 1998, n.d. (Box-folder 3:10)
- Client Files- Rudolph M. Kauffman, One West Melrose, Washington, D.C., 1934, n.d. (Box-folder 3:11)
- Client Files- Gordon Kennedy, 2915 Connecticut Avenue NW, Washington, D.C., 1946, n.d. (Box-folder 3:12)
- Client Files- Mrs. Arthur Kenny, Georgetown 1960s, n.d. (Box-folder 3:13)
- Client Files- Eugene Kienle, Clay Point, Milton Vermont, 1947-1948, 1948 (Box-folder 3:14)
- Client Files- Landon School, 1994 (Box-folder 3:15)
- Client Files- Mrs. C.C. Landing, Salisbury, Connecticut, 1929, 1934, n.d. (Box-folder 3:16)
- Client Files- John W. Laurence, Hartwood, Sharpsburg, Pennsylvania, 1938-1939, 1938 (Box-folder 3:17)
- Client Files- Colonel and Mrs. H.R. Le Clair, Friendship, Maryland, n.d. (Box-folder 3:18)
- Client Files- Mrs. and Mr. Robert Leighey, 1947, n.d. (Box-folder 3:19)
- Client Files- Mrs. A. Lorthrop Lutttrel, Old Georgetown Road (?), 1940, 1940 (Box-folder 3:20)
- Client Files- Madeira School, Greenway, Virginia, 1933, 1936, 1933-1961, 1997, n.d. (Box-folder 3:21)
- Client Files- Mrs. Paul Magnuson, 3121 0 Street NW, Washington, D.C., 1948-1949, 1951-1961, n.d. (Box-folder 3:22)
- Client Files- Rose Tucker Mason, Col Alto, Lexington, Virginia, 1984, 1988, n.d. (Box-folder 3:23)
- Client Files- Mrs. Paul McLean, 1925, n.d. (Box-folder 3:24)
- Client Files- Victor McQuade, Millbrook, New York, 1928, n.d. (Box-folder 3:25)
- Client Files- Paul Mellon, Belle Haven, Virginia, 1939-1940, n.d. (Box-folder 3:26)
- Client Files- Meridian Hill Park, 1985-1995 (Box-folder 3:27)
- Client Files- William Montgomery, Blythe Knoll, 6200 Nebraska Avenue NW, Washington, D.C. 1936-1950, 1936, 1948, 1996 (Box-folder 3:28)
- Client Files- Lewis N. Murray, Dunkirk, New York, 1932, 1934, n.d. (Box-folder 3:29)
- Client Files- George Hewitt Myers, 230-20 S Street NW, Washington, D.C., 1948, 1912, 1994, n.d. (Box-folder 3:30)
- Client Files- National Cathedral- Bishop's Garden, 1940, 1997, n.d. (Box-folder 3:31)
- Client Files- National Memorial Park, n.d. (Box-folder 3:32)
- Client Files- National Woman's Country Club, 1934 (Box-folder 3:33)
- Client Files- New York Military, Cornwall on the Hudson, New York, 1934, 1997 (Box-folder 3:34)
- Client Files- The Octagon, 1925, 1925, 1988-1998 (Box-folder 3:35)
- Client Files- Palace de la Liberte, Brussels, Belgium, n.d. (Box-folder 3:36)
  Memorial to King Albert.
- Client Files- Andrew Parker, 4000 Nebraska Avenue NW, Washington, D.C., 1943-1944, 1954 (Box-folder 3:37)
- Client Files- Siddy Thompkins Parker, 3001 Garrison Street, 1943 (Box-folder 3:38)
- Client Files- General Joseph D. Patch and Minerva King Patch, Patch Farms, Philomont Virginia, 1943, 45-60, 1998, n.d. (Box-folder 3:39)
- Client Files- Jefferson Patterson, Point Farm, Calvert County Maryland, 1996-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 3:40)
- Client Files- Paul Putzki, 4524 Garfield Street NW, Washington, D.C., n.d. (Box-folder 3:41)
- Client Files- Singleton Paull, Shawnee Hills, Wheeling WV, 1952, n.d. (Box-folder 3:42)
- Client Files- Mr. James H. Purdy, 2818 31st Street NW, Washington, D.C., 1947 (Box-folder 3:43)
- Client Files- Raymond Rebsamen, 2500 North Jackson Street, Little Rock, Arkansas, 1949-1950, 1995, n.d. (Box-folder 3:44)
- Client Files- Frederick Richards, Ridout Garden, Annapolis, Maryland, 1998, n.d. (Box-folder 3:45)
- Client Files- Paul Rosenberg, 3823 Massachusetts Avenue NW, n.d. (Box-folder 3:46)
- Client Files- Andrew Saul, 3035 Chain Bridge Road, Washington, D.C. 1941, 1941 (Box-folder 3:47)
- Client Files- General Julian Schley, 2815 Dumbarton Street NW, Washington, D.C., 1949, 1953, 1997, n.d. (Box-folder 3:48)
- Client Files- Mr. and Mrs. Samuel T. Schwartz, 2860 Woodland Drive, n.d. (Box-folder 3:49)
- Client Files- Albert Simms, Washington, D.C., 1932, 1929-1934, 1994-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 3:50)
- Client Files- Albert Simms, Los Poblamos Ranch, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1932-1934, 1990-2002, n.d. (Box-folder 3:51)
- Client Files- Lester Simpson, Marlan Forest, Alexandria, Virginia, 1951-1953, 1952 (Box-folder 3:52)
- Client Files- Mrs. Sherman, 29 Kalorama Circle, Washington, D.C., 1944, 1944, n.d. (Box-folder 3:53)
- Client Files- Lester Shomo, 631 Oakland Terrace, Alexandria, Virginia, 1952, 1955, n.d. (Box-folder 3:54)
- Client Files- Francis Sortwell, Volta Place, Washington, D.C., 1934, n.d. (Box-folder 4:1)
- Client Files- Dorothy Stead, 3216 O Street, Washington, D.C., 1955, n.d. (Box-folder 4:2)
- Client Files- L. Corrin Strong, Gibson, Maryland, 1998, n.d. (Box-folder 4:3)
- Client Files- Charles Tampkins, Battery Terrill 3000 Garrison Street, Washington, D.C., n.d. (Box-folder 4:4)
- Client Files- William H. Taylor, 1537 Q Street NW, Washington, D.C., 1936-1937, n.d. (Box-folder 4:5)
- Client Files- St. Timothy's School, Stevenson, Maryland, 1952-1954, n.d. (Box-folder 4:6)
- Client Files- John T. Tyssowiki Cobbler Mountain Farm Deleplane, Virginia, 1947, 1947, 1996, n.d. (Box-folder 4:7)
- Client Files- A.A. Vandergrift, Commandant's House, 1944, 1972-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 4:8)
- Client Files- Albert W. Walker, 6701 Hillandale, Westmoreland, 1949-1951, 1997, n.d. (Box-folder 4:9)
- Client Files- Albert W. Walker, Cottage 102, Sea Island Georgia, 1949-1950, 1941, 1997-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
- Client Files- Thomas Murray Wilson, 1946, n.d. (Box-folder 4:11)
- Client Files- The Washington City Hillcrest Orphanage, Washington, D.C., 1926-1928, 1926-1963, 1996-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 4:12)
- Client Files- George Wheeler, 2510 Foxhall Road NW, Washington, D.C., 1951, 1996, n.d. (Box-folder 4:13)
- Correspondence- John Greely, 1906-1991, n.d. (Box-folder 4:14)
- Correspondence concerning Rose Greely- Pending, 1994-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 4:15)
- Correspondence of Rose Greely (Copies), 1901-1994, n.d. (Box-folder 4:16)
- Correspondence- Historical Society of Washington, D.C., 1997-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 4:17)
- Mary P. Cunningham, 1930-1976, n.d. (Box-folder 4:18)
- Dead Ends Research File, 1996-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 4:19)
- Exhibit Boards, n.d. (Oversize 4)
- Exhibit Ideas, 1984-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 4:20)
- Exhibit Packet, [1998] (Box-folder 4:21)
- Exhibit Proposal, 1995-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 4:22)
- Exhibit Proposal Mailing List, 1996-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 4:23)
- Charles F. Gillette, n.d. (Box-folder 5:1)
- Beatrice C. Horneman, 1943, 1998 (Box-folder 5:2)
- Lectures, Symposia, etc., 1993-2000 (Box-folder 5:3)
- Lowthrope School of Landscape Architecture for Women, 1912-1940, 1999, n.d. (Box-folder 5:4)
- Lowthrope School of Landscape Architecture for Women, Groton, Massachusetts-Thesis by Jane Alison Knight, 1986 (Box-folder 5:5)
- Library of Congress Research, 1996 (Box-folder 5:6)
- Charles Merryman, 1917-1994 (Box-folder 5:7)
- Negatives, n.d. (Box-folder 5:8)
- Notes concerning Research on Rose Greely Projects, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 5:9)
- Notes concerning Research on Rose Greely Projects, n.d. (Box-folder 5:10)
- Cary Millholland Parker, 1946, 1996, n.d. (Box-folder 5:11)
- Horace W. Peaslee, 1934-1998 (Box-folder 5:12)
- Phone Interviews, 1996-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 5:13)
- Photographs of Rose Greely, n.d. (Box-folder 5:14)
- Photographs, n.d. (Box-folder 5:15)
- Photographs, n.d. (Box-folder 5:16)
- Photographs, n.d. (Oversize 5)
- Poems by Rose Greely, 1907-1912, n.d. (Box-folder 6:1)
- Professional Contacts, 1996-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 6:2)
- Research Sources, 1984-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 6:3)
- Slide Lecture, n.d. (Box-folder 6:4)
- Slides (1 of 3 folders), n.d. (Box-folder 6:5)
- Slides (2 of 3 folders), n.d. (Box-folder 6:6)
- Slides (3 of 3 folders), n.d. (Box-folder 6:7)
- Talks concerning Rose Greely, 1995, n.d. (Box-folder 6:8)
- Thesis in the School of Domestic Architecture and Landscape Architecture at Cambridge, Massachusetts- Report on a Proposed Cooperative Farm Community- by Rose Greely, 1920 (Box-folder 6:9)
- Thesis in Architecture and Landscape Architecture- A Redesign of a Rural New England Community by Rose Greely, 1919 (Box-folder 6:10)
- Thesis- Rose Greely, FASLA Her Life and Work by Joanne Seal Lawson, 1993 May (Box-folder 6:11)
- Thesis- Rose Greely, FASLA Her Life and Work- by Joanne Seal Lawson, 1993 May (Box-folder 7:1)
- Thesis Drafts (1 of 2 folders), [ante 1993] (Box-folder 7:2)
- Thesis Drafts (2 of 2 folders), [ante 1993] (Box-folder 7:3)
- Thesis Illustrations (Copies), [ante 1993] (Box-folder 7:4)
- Thesis- Notes and Drafts, ca. 1993 (Box-folder 7:5)
- Tradesmen and Other Professionals in DC Area, 1940 (Box-folder 7:6)
- Williamsburg, Virginia, 1930-1992, n.d. (Box-folder 7:7)
- Waddy Wood, 1994 (Box-folder 7:8)